<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Arjun Jayaprakash</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Arjun Jayaprakash</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Statement</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/04/08/research-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/04/08/research-statement/</guid>
      <description>My short-term research goal is to contribute to the field of structural engineering by focusing on two specific areas:
 Experimental and computational methods for assessment and retrofitting of existing infrastructure
 Performance based design of structural systems against natural hazards  Large Scale Experiments of Structures In 2017, American Society of Civil Engineers published a comprehensive infrastructure report card for the United States that gave an overall grade of D+.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balance Ratio to Characterize Earthquake Loading History - A pilot study</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/04/06/balance-ratio-to-characterize-earthquake-loading-history-a-pilot-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/04/06/balance-ratio-to-characterize-earthquake-loading-history-a-pilot-study/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Earthquake “hazard” is a technical term for a quantitiy or a series of quanitites that captures the effect of an earthquake ground motion on structures. For instance, the peak ground acceleration (PGA) is an extremely simple representation of an earthquake. It essentially is the maximum ground acceleration value observed at a site during an earthquake. Does this tell us everything we want to know about an earthquake? Of course not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Durability of Cementitious Grouts in Cold Climate</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/03/02/durability-of-cementitious-grouts-in-cold-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/03/02/durability-of-cementitious-grouts-in-cold-climate/</guid>
      <description> Background and Motivation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Consequences of Grout Deterioration in the Grouted Shear Stud Connections</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/02/20/structural-consequences-in-gss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/02/20/structural-consequences-in-gss/</guid>
      <description>Background and Motivation The Grouted Shear Stud Connection In steel bridge substructures, the conventional practice for connecting the steel columns/piles to the cap beam was through a direct weld. This is shown in the figure below. The yellow oval encircles the region where the column is directly welded to the cap beam.
 Figure 1: From a bridge in Alaska, USA  However, these kind of connections were tested in the lab a few years ago under cyclic lateral loading, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensitivity of NLTH Analysis of MDOF Bridges to Choice of Viscous Damping Models</title>
      <link>/projects/2017/04/27/sensitivity-of-nlth-analysis-of-mdof-bridges-to-choice-of-viscous-damping-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2017/04/27/sensitivity-of-nlth-analysis-of-mdof-bridges-to-choice-of-viscous-damping-models/</guid>
      <description>Introduction There has been a rising interest among engineers to conduct non-linear time history (NLTH) analysis as part of the seismic design procedure for bridges. A good understanding of member parameters such as strength, stiffness and damping are crucial for accurate results from NLTH analysis. Strength and stiffness in dynamic analyses are well understood but the viscous damping model that is mostly being used in commercial analysis programs, namely initial stiffness proportional Rayleigh damping, is questionable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>