<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Arjun Jayaprakash</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Arjun Jayaprakash</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Balance Ratio to Characterize Earthquake Loading History - A pilot study</title>
      <link>/projects/2020/01/30/balance-ratio-to-characterize-earthquake-loading-history-a-pilot-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2020/01/30/balance-ratio-to-characterize-earthquake-loading-history-a-pilot-study/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Abstract: Recent studies have revealed the impact of ground motion loading history on performance limit-states of RC bridge columns such as longitudinal reinforcement bar-buckling and residual drift ratio. Conventional hazard characterizations such as peak ground acceleration, spectral acceleration, and spectral displacement can only capture peak values of ground motion hazard and therefore fall short of providing the necessary information to account for these limit-states. In this study, a parameter termed as the opposite peak ratio is defined, explored, and shown to be useful in reproducing loading history characteristics of ground motions for displacement-based design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Statement</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/09/28/research-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/09/28/research-statement/</guid>
      <description>My research interests fall within the broad area of performance-based seismic design and assessment (PBSE). A major advantage of performance-based principles is the capability to map conventional structural limit states on to clear decision variables such as economic losses or savings. For example, while designing a new multi-storey building, it is now possible for an engineer to quantify and communicate the probability of incurring a certain amount of monetary loss in a given period of time or under a specific natural hazard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Statement</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/04/08/research-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/04/08/research-statement/</guid>
      <description>My short-term research goal is to contribute to the field of structural engineering by focusing on two specific areas:
 Experimental and computational methods for assessment and retrofitting of existing infrastructure
 Performance based design of structural systems against natural hazards  Large Scale Experiments of Structures In 2017, American Society of Civil Engineers published a comprehensive infrastructure report card for the United States that gave an overall grade of D+.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Durability of Cementitious Grouts in Cold Climate</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/03/02/durability-of-cementitious-grouts-in-cold-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/03/02/durability-of-cementitious-grouts-in-cold-climate/</guid>
      <description> Background and Motivation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Consequences of Grout Deterioration in the Grouted Shear Stud Connections</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/02/20/structural-consequences-in-gss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/02/20/structural-consequences-in-gss/</guid>
      <description>Background and Motivation The Grouted Shear Stud Connection In steel bridge substructures, the conventional practice for connecting the steel columns/piles to the cap beam was through a direct weld. This is shown in the figure below. The yellow oval encircles the region where the column is directly welded to the cap beam.
 Figure 1: From a bridge in Alaska, USA  However, these kind of connections were tested in the lab a few years ago under cyclic lateral loading, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensitivity of NLTH Analysis of MDOF Bridges to Choice of Viscous Damping Models</title>
      <link>/projects/2017/04/27/sensitivity-of-nlth-analysis-of-mdof-bridges-to-choice-of-viscous-damping-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2017/04/27/sensitivity-of-nlth-analysis-of-mdof-bridges-to-choice-of-viscous-damping-models/</guid>
      <description>Introduction There has been a rising interest among engineers to conduct non-linear time history (NLTH) analysis as part of the seismic design procedure for bridges. A good understanding of member parameters such as strength, stiffness and damping are crucial for accurate results from NLTH analysis. Strength and stiffness in dynamic analyses are well understood but the viscous damping model that is mostly being used in commercial analysis programs, namely initial stiffness proportional Rayleigh damping, is questionable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>