<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Arjun Jayaprakash</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Arjun Jayaprakash</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python 1</title>
      <link>/post/2019/06/25/python-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/06/25/python-1/</guid>
      <description>First lessons Here is how a simple code looks like. Saving variables as int (integers) or float (floating points) are shown.
 Exponentiation: ** This operator raises the number to its left to the power of the number to its right.
 Modulo: %. This operator returns the remainder of the division of the number to the left by the number on its right.
  # Create a variable savings savings = 100 # Create a variable growth_multiplier growth_multiplier = 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Statement</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/04/08/research-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/04/08/research-statement/</guid>
      <description>My short-term research goal is to contribute to the field of structural engineering by focusing on two specific areas:
 Experimental and computational methods for assessment and retrofitting of existing infrastructure
 Performance based design of structural systems against natural hazards  Large Scale Experiments of Structures In 2017, American Society of Civil Engineers published a comprehensive infrastructure report card for the United States that gave an overall grade of D+.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Statement</title>
      <link>/post/2019/04/08/teaching-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/04/08/teaching-statement/</guid>
      <description>My approach to teaching an undergraduate level course is different from my plan to teach a graduate level course. My experience from observing and teaching the statics course, as well as having been an undergraduate student, has lead me to believe that a majority of the students find it hard to make the transition from high school to college level. Hence, my philosophy for teaching fundamental courses like statics, mechanics of solids, reinforced concrete etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balance Ratio to Characterize Earthquake Loading History - A pilot study</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/04/06/balance-ratio-to-characterize-earthquake-loading-history-a-pilot-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/04/06/balance-ratio-to-characterize-earthquake-loading-history-a-pilot-study/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Earthquake “hazard” is a technical term for a quantitiy or a series of quanitites that captures the effect of an earthquake ground motion on structures. For instance, the peak ground acceleration (PGA) is an extremely simple representation of an earthquake. It essentially is the maximum ground acceleration value observed at a site during an earthquake. Does this tell us everything we want to know about an earthquake? Of course not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elimination method</title>
      <link>/post/2019/03/14/elimination-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/03/14/elimination-method/</guid>
      <description>Basic concept It is all about solving a system of simultaneous linear equations, referring back to high school maths. Say we have,
\[ x + 2y + z = 2\] \[ 3x + 8y + z = 12\] \[ 4y + z = 2\]
we can convert this set of equations into a single equation through matrices. Just compile all the coefficients onto a matrix \(\textbf{A}\) and the variables into an unknown vector \(\textbf{x}\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro</title>
      <link>/post/2019/03/14/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/03/14/intro/</guid>
      <description>About the series I have been watching MIT Open Courseware lectures on Linear Algebra by Dr. Gilbert Strang to refresh my memory of the concepts. I had watched this series a couple of years ago while I was taking the Advanced Finite Element course at my university. At that time, I thought I had a good grasp of the concepts. However, two years of non-usage has left me completely ignorant of the core concepts of matrix operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Durability of Cementitious Grouts in Cold Climate</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/03/02/durability-of-cementitious-grouts-in-cold-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/03/02/durability-of-cementitious-grouts-in-cold-climate/</guid>
      <description> Background and Motivation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R for engineers - Basics</title>
      <link>/resources/blogs/r-for-engineers-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/blogs/r-for-engineers-basics/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in a series of posts where I go over some R syntax useful for engineers. I am in no way an expert in R programming, but have been using it to read, analyze and visualize the data I obtain from both physical experiments as well as simulations. The R coding I will be discussing may therefore not be the most efficient way to solve problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Consequences of Grout Deterioration in the Grouted Shear Stud Connections</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/02/20/structural-consequences-in-gss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/02/20/structural-consequences-in-gss/</guid>
      <description>Background and Motivation The Grouted Shear Stud Connection In steel bridge substructures, the conventional practice for connecting the steel columns/piles to the cap beam was through a direct weld. This is shown in the figure below. The yellow oval encircles the region where the column is directly welded to the cap beam.
 Figure 1: From a bridge in Alaska, USA  However, these kind of connections were tested in the lab a few years ago under cyclic lateral loading, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this website</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever had this happen to you when a great idea pops up in your head from nowhere and you feel, &amp;ldquo;Wow, this is a great idea, I need to write this down, hmm&amp;hellip; maybe later!&amp;rdquo; A few hours later, you don&amp;rsquo;t even remember the existence of the idea.
I have had that happen multiple times to me and one reason for not being able to follow up on ideas that my past self has had was lack of a specific space that I can quickly note it down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Python - Py series</title>
      <link>/post/1/01/01/learning-python-py-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/1/01/01/learning-python-py-series/</guid>
      <description>About the series So, I decided to give Python a try. This blog series is just me jotting down whatever I learn in Python. This isn’t a tutorial since I am a beginner myself. However, this may serve as a good resource for beginners like me.
 Chapters  Python 1  Sources Please note that the example code chunks I am using here weren’t developed by myself. I am collating these from multiple sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Articles  Jayaprakash, A., Nau, J., Pour-Ghaz, M., and Kowalsky, M., “Structural Consequences of Grout Deterioration in the Grouted Shear Stud Connection”. Bridge Engineering Institute. 2019
 Jayaprakash, A., and Kowalsky, M., “Balance Ratio to Characterize Earthquake Loading History for Performance Based Design”. 12th Canadian Conference on Earthquake Engineering. 2019
   Reports  Jayaprakash, A., Price, C., Jiang, A., Pour-Ghaz, M., Nau, J., and Kowalsky, M., “Comparison of Cylinder and Cube Strength for Typical Grouts”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Read my full research statement here.
Projects Structural Consequences of the Grouted Shear Stud Connection The grouted shear stud (GSS) connection is a steel bridge column to cap-beam connection developed as an alternative to conventional directly welded connections. The directly welded connections have been shown to fail prematurely in a brittle fashion which is undesirable for seismic design. The GSS connection eliminates any failure at the weld interface by relocating failure on to the columns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description> Read my full teaching statement here.
Courses  Statics   Blog Tutorials  R for Engineers I   Learning Series  Python Linear Algebra   Q &amp;amp; A  Recommendations Online Learning Portals  MIT Open Courseware EdX DataCamp    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>