<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Structures on Arjun Jayaprakash</title>
    <link>/categories/structures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Structures on Arjun Jayaprakash</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/structures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Mechanics - Statics</title>
      <link>/resources/courses/statics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/courses/statics/</guid>
      <description>Statics deals with the equilibrium of bodies, that is, those that are either at rest or move with a constant velocity. The most effective way of learning the principles of engineering mechanics is to solve as many problems as you can. Here is a generic suggestive list of the steps you take to solve problems in mechanics (Adapted from Engineering mechanics, 14th edition, Hibbeler).
 Read the problem carefully and try to correlate the actual physical situation with the theory studied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balance Ratio to Characterize Earthquake Loading History - A pilot study</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/04/06/balance-ratio-to-characterize-earthquake-loading-history-a-pilot-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/04/06/balance-ratio-to-characterize-earthquake-loading-history-a-pilot-study/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Earthquake “hazard” is a technical term for a quantitiy or a series of quanitites that captures the effect of an earthquake ground motion on structures. For instance, the peak ground acceleration (PGA) is an extremely simple representation of an earthquake. It essentially is the maximum ground acceleration value observed at a site during an earthquake. Does this tell us everything we want to know about an earthquake? Of course not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Durability of Cementitious Grouts in Cold Climate</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/03/02/durability-of-cementitious-grouts-in-cold-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/03/02/durability-of-cementitious-grouts-in-cold-climate/</guid>
      <description> Background and Motivation  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>