<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Structures on Arjun Jayaprakash</title>
    <link>/categories/structures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Structures on Arjun Jayaprakash</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/structures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Balance Ratio to Characterize Earthquake Loading History - A pilot study</title>
      <link>/projects/2020/01/30/balance-ratio-to-characterize-earthquake-loading-history-a-pilot-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2020/01/30/balance-ratio-to-characterize-earthquake-loading-history-a-pilot-study/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Abstract: Recent studies have revealed the impact of ground motion loading history on performance limit-states of RC bridge columns such as longitudinal reinforcement bar-buckling and residual drift ratio. Conventional hazard characterizations such as peak ground acceleration, spectral acceleration, and spectral displacement can only capture peak values of ground motion hazard and therefore fall short of providing the necessary information to account for these limit-states. In this study, a parameter termed as the opposite peak ratio is defined, explored, and shown to be useful in reproducing loading history characteristics of ground motions for displacement-based design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Mechanics - Statics</title>
      <link>/resources/courses/statics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/courses/statics/</guid>
      <description>Statics deals with the equilibrium of bodies, that is, those that are either at rest or move with a constant velocity. The most effective way of learning the principles of engineering mechanics is to solve as many problems as you can. Here is a generic suggestive list of the steps you take to solve problems in mechanics (Adapted from Engineering mechanics, 14th edition, Hibbeler).
 Read the problem carefully and try to correlate the actual physical situation with the theory studied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Durability of Cementitious Grouts in Cold Climate</title>
      <link>/projects/2019/03/02/durability-of-cementitious-grouts-in-cold-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2019/03/02/durability-of-cementitious-grouts-in-cold-climate/</guid>
      <description> Background and Motivation  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>